In the next lessons,
في الدروس التالية،
we will discuss how to use statistics to describe quantitative data.
سنناقش كيفية استخدام الإحصائيات لوصف البيانات الكمية.
You will gain insight into a process of how data is
وستكتسب فكرة واضحة في عملية كيفية
collected and how to answer questions using your data.
جمع البيانات وكيفية الإجابة عن الأسئلة باستخدام بياناتك.
Throughout this lesson, I hope you learn to be critical of
وخلال هذا الدرس، أود أن تتعلموا كيف تنتقدوا
your analysis that happened under the hood and what the numbers actually mean.
تحليلكم الذي أنشأتموه ضمن هذا الإطار وما تعنيه الأرقام بالفعل.
As an example of an analysis that we do here at Udacity,
وكمثال على التحليل الذي نقوم به هنا في Udacity،
we look at how long a nanodegree program takes students to complete.
إننا ننظر إلى المدة التي يستغرقها الطلاب لإكمال برنامج nanodegree.
We try to provide an estimate of the number of months or hours that students will spend.
ونحاول تقديم رقم تقريبي لعدد الشهور أو الساعات التي سيقضيها الطلاب.
One way we might start is by reporting
وإحدى الطرق التي يمكن أن نبدأ بها
the average amount of time it takes to complete the nanodegree program.
هي تقديم متوسط الوقت المُستغرق لإكمال برنامج nanodegree.
But that doesn't tell the whole story.
إلا أن هذا لا يصف الأمر برمته.
I'm sure there are differences in completion
فأنا على يقين من وجود اختلافات في مدة إكمال البرنامج
depending on what students knew before entering the program.
بناء على ما عرفه الطلاب قبل البدء في البرنامج.
The shortest amount of time needed to complete
مع ملاحظة أن أقصر وقت ممكن لإكمال
the nanodegree program might just be a few weeks.
برنامج nanodegree قد يكون بضعة أسابيع فقط.
How did those people complete the course so fast?
كيف أكمل هؤلاء الأشخاص الدورة بهذه السرعة؟
Well, the longest might be a couple of years.
حسنًا، قد تكون أطول مدة ممكنة هي عامين.
What proportion of students finish fast within two months?
ما نسبة الطلاب الذين يكملون البرنامج بسرعة في غضون شهرين؟
What proportion take longer than eight months?
وما نسبة الطلاب الذين استغرقوا فترة أكبر من ثمانية أشهر؟
Using a variety of measures,
باستخدام مجموعة متنوعة من التدابير،
like measures of center,
مثل تدابير المركز،
give you an idea of the average student.
تحصل على فكرة عن الطالب المتوسط.
Measures of spread give you an idea of how students differ.
كما تمنحك تدابير الانتشار فكرة عن مدى اختلاف الطلاب.
Visuals can provide us
إلى جانب ذلك، يمكن أن توفر لنا المرئيات
a more complete picture of how long it takes any student to complete a program.
صورة أكثر اكتمالاً عن المدة التي يستغرقها أي طالب لإكمال البرنامج.
The material in the next sections will show you how to use
كما ستوضح لك المواد الموجودة في الأقسام التالية كيفية استخدام
these measures in a way that is informative and understandable to others.
هذه التدابير بطريقة مفيدة ومفهومة للآخرين.